# Lama Osman

# Python Back-End Developer

A mathematician with background in research, education and data analysis as well as knowledge of C++, Matlab and SQL.Good social skills and a team Player spirit.

After one year of full time further education (Training) in python backend development and practical projects in Data Science I am seeking a job to apply and develop my knowledge of both fields.

#### **SPECIALS**

- Interest and knowledge of Data Science and ML
- Project Management tools
- Agile Development
- Inability to give up on hard problems, a balanced form of perfectionism, a positive can-do attitude and the ability to work independently

#### **SKILLS**

• Technologies: HTML &CSS 00P: Python & C++ Rest API GCP &AWS

Git & GitHub

Django & DRF FastAPI Pandas & NumPy Scrapy

• Frameworks:

• <u>Databases:</u> RDBMS SQL, SQLite3 Postgresql

• Other: CI/CD TDD Scrum Design Pat

Matlab linux/Ubuntu Shell Scripts

#### <u>Languages</u>

Arabic: Native

Scikit Learn

German: Full professional proficiency English: Professional working proficiency

#### **Contact**



(+49) 176-31 50 87 21



<u>Todtnauer Zeile 3, 13469 Berlin</u>



la.osm.jobs@gmail.com







#### Education

#### Python Backend Programming (2022 -2023)

Digital Career Institute gGmbH, Berlin

- One year full-time training on Python basics, Databases, Django, Django rest Framework, Fast API, Rest APIs, Cloud services, Docker Container, Git/GitHub, CI/CD and design patterns
- English classes | B2/C1

#### Data Circle Program (2022- Now)

ReDi School, Berlin

- 4 month evening training, 10 h weekly
- Practical team projects in Data Science
- Web Scraping and Recommendations (ML)

#### Functional Analysis (Stochastic Analysis) (2008 -2011)

PhD Program, TU Kaiserslautern

- White Noise Analysis, stochastic PDE, Feynman Integrals
- Not finished due to syrian war conditions

#### Applicable Analysis and Probability (2004 -2007)

Master of Science, TU Kaiserslautern

- Focus on Geomathematics, minor Physics
- programming and using: Matlab, LaTeX, C++

#### Pure Mathematics and Algebra (1996 - 2002)

Diplom Study, Aleppo University, Aleppo

• Best of the Year with "Al Basel" Certificate of Honor

## Experience

### Teacher for Mathematics and Physics (2015 - 2021)

Berlin Senate Department of Education, Family and Youth

- 7th 11th grades
- Applying the "Design Thinking methods" as Teamwork with other colleagues
- Building and development of E- Learning in Corona time
- Integration class "German as second Language"

#### Co- Worker in Risk Management Department (2013-2014)

Klarna GmbH (Billpay previously), Berlin

- Data Analysis with Excel and PostgreSQL in E-Commerce
- Automation of the KPI Reports with VBA and SQL
- Query optimization in cooperation with operation team
- Learning the concepts of "risk management" and "decision making process" in the field of "online payment services"

#### Asylum Procedure (2011-2013)

BAMF, Trier

• Translator for other refugees

#### Assistant Lecturer for Mathematics (2003-2004)

Informatics Department, Aleppo University, Aleppo

• Obtained full scholarship for a Promotion in Germany

03.01.2023, Jama Osman.